## Haider M. Hausawi

### Telecom Engineer

More than 3 years' experience, as a systems administrator assistant, help desk & network technician, as well as web developer & marketing assistant in (E-commerce and Facebook pages sector). I have monitor several network systems, security systems (Zkteco), cctv, troubleshoot issues & optimize network stability performance, I increased the number of visitors there by 30% and increased the conversion rate from 1.8% to 4.2%, I also have ability to design & develop static & dynamic websites, APIs, & web App.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES**

December 2022 - Now

Libya, Misuratta

Freelancer web developer (E-commerce, Blog websites and Facebookpages monitoring)

- build websites and web applications that meet project objectives and provide a positive user experience.
- writing codes, testing codes, altering codes, and fixing several types of errors.
- Ensure the website is visually appealing and easy to navigate,
- Develop and test new applications, or monitor site performance and traffic

November 2021 – December 2022

#### Almotkaml co. for IT management & services, Tripoli

Systems Administrator

- Installing, configuring, and maintaining network hardware and software such as routers, firewalls, switches, cctv cameras, & ZKteco Biotime Security systems equipment
- Providing remote technical support over the phone or internet.
- Manage communications between product, IT and content customers.
- Plan and carry out social media marketing campaigns
- Analyze the customer database to optimize automatic emails.

October 2020 – September 2021

Vision Enterprise, Khartoum

Network technician

Maintain network servers and associated hardware, software, services, and settings

Recommend, test, and implement system and security upgrades Consistently monitor and troubleshoot network stability and performance

Create, adjust, and maintain network user settings and permissions Write technical support documentation for network systems and applications

April 2020 – September 2020

Voice of mind association, Khartoum

Help desk technician (6-month internship)

- Diagnosing and solving computer issues.
- Installing and training end users in new technologies.
- Providing remote technical support over the phone or internet.
- Backing up and restoring data files.
- Repairing hardware and configuring software to maintain operating systems



#### CONTACT

#### **Address**

Mugawba - Misuratta, Libya

**Phone** 0912858198

Email bayajidabarack@proto n.me

#### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic, mother tongue

Hausa (C2 Level)

English (B2 Level)

German (A1)

#### Personal info

Birth: 15th Oct 1987

Marital status: Merried

Nationality: Sudanese

# **Haider Hausawi**

## Telecom Engineer

#### **EDUCATION**

September 2015 – September 2018

**Telecommunications Engineering** (Diploma) **Omderman** Al-ahlia University, Sudan **English language communication**, Marcony Academy – *Omderman, Sudan* 

September 2018 - June 2020

Websites developing, Comptia A+ and digital marketing, Sudan CCNA, MCSA, Virtualization, Helper Center Cairo, Egypt

#### **SKILLS**

- Design and organizing databases, managing database access, Optimizing database performance, Secure, backup and restore database, Debug and resolve script conflicts, & Debug and resolve script conflicts, & Ensuring data integrity.
- Installing, configuring, and maintaining network hardware and software such as routers, firewalls, switches, cctv, cameras, & Attendance prefirals.
- identifying and solving any problems that arise with computer networks and systems
- maintaining existing software and hardware and upgrading any that have become obsolete
- Html, Css, Python, Bootstrap, framework (WordPress & Django) and SQL database optimization Online store optimization (conversion rate, visits)
- Soft skill (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, outlook)
- Cisco Packet Tracer
- GNS3 (Graphical Network Simulator 3)
- Communication

#### **HOBBIES**

Script Coding

Instructing

Media content creation

WordPress Designing

Search engine optimization (SEO)

Social services volunteering